SUBHAM CHAR



charvai1997@gmail.com



Manbazar, West Bengal, India



SUMMARY

With 4 years of experience, I specialize in Full-Stack Development, covering technologies like JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express.js and MongoDB. I also excel in using AWS, TypeScript, Git, and Micro Frontends, while leading teams and driving efficient solutions in Blockchain and REST API development.

SKILLS

- JavaScript TypeScript ReactJs ExpressJs
- NodeJs MongoDB HTML CSS Git AWS

Senior Software Engineer

• SCSS • Tailwind CSS • Redux • SocketIO • REST APIs • NextJS • Firebase • React Query • Micro Frontend • Blockchain

EDUCATION

BENGAL COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY

B.Tech (Information Technology) 2016 - 2020

MANBAR RADHA MADHAB INSTITUTION

12TH (Science) 2015 - 2016

MANBAR RADHA MADHAB INSTITUTION

2013 - 2014

CERTIFICATIONS

• The Complete Web Developer in 2020: Zero to Mastery

LINK

- linkedin.com/in/subham-char
- github.com/svarcoder
- svarcoder.github.io/my-website

LANGUAGES

- English
- Bengali
- Hindi

INTEREST

- Open-Source Contributation.
- · New Technology.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Arcana Network | Senior Software Developer

09/2024 - Present | Bengaluru, India

- Developed and Maintained Web App that used with React, Node, Express, MongoDB, AWS and Typescript.
- Working in Frontend Technologies for handle React Application.

Comdex | Senior Software Developer

04/2023 - 06/2024 | Bengaluru, India

- Developed and Maintained Web App that used with React, Node, Express, MongoDB, AWS and Typescript and Micro Frontend Technologies .
- · Create and manage RESTFUL APIs In Node, Express, MongoDB to support the frontend.

Rapid Innovation | Software Developer

10/2021 - 03/2023 | Noida, India

- Lead Development Teams in the delivery of high-quality Frontend Application in React JS with Scalability, Performance, Security requirements.
- Manage User Authentication using JWT, Cross-Browser Compatibility. and Optimize the application for Performance and Responsiveness.

Techbae Pty Ltd | Full Stack Developer

10/2020 - 10/2021 | Melbourne, AU

- Developed and Maintained Web App that used with React, Node, Express, Mongo, AWS and Typescript managed by AWS Lambda, S3, API Gateway.
- Deployed React.js Application with Redux, Typescript, CSS, which contain multiple themes and in Backend in Node, Express, MongoDB.

PROJECTS

All In Bets

Technologies Used: MERN, Micro Frontend, TS, AWS

Design and Developed Frontend and Backend. Created APIs and Implemented in frontend. Also implement Socket and Firebase Notification with AWS Deployment. Optimization Frontend.

White Label

Technologies Used: MERN, TypeScript, AWS

Design and Developed Frontend and Backend. Created APIs and Implemented in frontend. Optimization Frontend.